The Guide to the John Canemaker Animation Collection 1903-2012 (Bulk 1970-2000) MSS 040
Fales Library and Special Collections
This subseries includes research notes, interviews and other material related to Canemaker's book "Walt Disney's Nine Old Men and the Art of Animation."
Subseries D: Chuck Jones
This subseries includes research notes, interviews, and other material related to Canemaker's short film "Chuck Jones: Memories of Childhood."
Subseries E: John and Faith Hubley
This subseries includes research notes, correspondence, and other material related to the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences program "A Salute to John & Faith Hubley."
Subseries F: "The Moon and the Son"
This subseries includes research notes, correspondence, and other material related to Canemaker's Academy Award-winning short film "The Moon and the Son."
Subseries G: "Two Guys Named Joe"
This subseries includes research notes, correspondence, and other material related to Canemaker's book "Two Guys Named Joe."
SERIES VII: Objects(added with 2008 Accretion)
Series VII consists of promotional objects associated with commercial films acquired by Canemaker.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject/author heading.
The files are grouped into seven series.
Accretions are listed at the end of the container list and mirror the original organizational structure of the collection.
Series I: Documentary Material
Series II: Graphic Material
Series III: Book Collection
Series IV: Periodical Collection
Series V: Audio & Video Tape Collection
Oversize - Series I: Documentary Material
Oversize - Series II: Graphic Material
Accretions 2000 - Series I: Documentary Material
Accretions 2000 - Oversize - Series I: Documentary Material
Accretions 2001 - Series I: Documentary Material
Accretions 2001 - Oversize - Series I: Documentary Material
Accretions 2001 - Oversize - Series II: Graphic Material
Accretions 2003 - Series I: Documentary Material
Accretions 2003 - Series II: Graphic Material
Accretions 2003 - Series VI: Major Projects
Accretions 2003 - Oversize - Series II: Graphic Material
Accretions 2008 - Series I: Documentary Material
Accretions 2008 - Series II: Graphic Material
Accretions 2008 - Series III: Book Collection
Accretions 2008 - Series IV: Periodical Collection
Accretions 2008 - Series V: Audio & Video Tape Collection
Accretions 2008 - Series VI: Major Projects
Accretions 2008 - Series VII: Objects
Accretions 2008 - Oversize - Series I: Documentary Material
Accretions 2012 - Series I: Documentary Material
Accretions 2012 - Series IV: Periodical Collection
Accretions 2012 - Series V: Audio & Video Tape Collection
Accretions 2012 - Series VI: Major Projects
Accretions 2012 - Oversize - Series I - Documentary Material
Accretions 2012 - Oversize - Series VI - Major Projects
Separated Material
Some 14 video tapes and over 100 audio tapes of interviews, lectures, and seminars were originally donated to the Avery Fisher Center for Music and Media, in Bobst Library, in 1988. In the summer of 2003, the audiorecordings were transferred to the Fales Library where they are now listed as part of the John Canemaker Animation Collection. The videotapes remain in the Avery Fisher Center for Music and Media.
The following books and periodicals have been separated from the collection, are individually cataloged through BobCat.
Periodicals
American Cinematographer. Vol. 58, No. 10; October, 1977.
American Film. Vol. 2, No. 8; June 1977.
Animafilm. No. 2, 3, 8, 11; 1980 87 (gaps). Turin, Italy.
Animania. No. 20; February, 1981. Minneapolis, MN.
Animation Magazine. Vol. 1, No. 1, 2 3; August, December, 1987.
Animation Magazine. Vol. 7, 4, Vol 10, 7; 1994-96 (gaps).
Animation Magazine. Vol 10, 9,10, Vol 11, 1; October, November 1996, February 1997.
Animation Magazine. Vol. 19, Issue 7, No. 150; July 2005.
Animator. No. 18; Jan./Mar., 1987. Herts, England.
Animator. No. 29; Fall 1982. Portland, Oregon.
Animator. No. 40; Spring, 1987. Portland, Oregon.
Animazine No. 16 20; May 1984-September 1985. Toronto, Canada.
ASIFA San Francisco Newsletter. June 1988.
ASIFA Canada. Vol 24, No. 2; September 1996..
Banc-Titre. No. 19; 1982. Paris, France.
Cartoonist Profiles. No. 46, 47, 74, 75; 1980 87 (gaps). Westport, CT.
Cinefantastique. Vol. 5, No. 3 (n.d.).
Cinefantastique. Vol. 28, No. 12; June, 1997.
Cinema. Vol. 1, No. 3; September/October 1996. Brazil.
Cinemagic. No. 36 (n.d.).
Collectibles Illustrated. Vol. 2, No. 1; Jan./Feb. 1983.
Collectors' Showcase. Vol. 15, No. 4, Vol. 16, No. 1,7, Vol. 17, No. 1,6; August/September 1995, February/March, November 1996, January/February, November/December 1997.
Collectors' Showcase. Vol. 16, No. 6,7; September, November, 1996.
Crain's New York Business. Vol. 13, No. 1; January 6-12, 1997.
Daily Variety. 75 Years of Disney Magic; June 26, 1998.
Diamond Dialogue. July, 1993, February, 1996.
Disney Magazine. Fall 1996, Winter 1998-1999.
Disney Magazine. Winter 1997-1998.
Disney News. Winter 1983, Summer 1987, Fall 1987, Winter 1989.
En Coulisse. No. 9; March 1994. France.
Entertainment Weekly. No. 354; November 22, 1996.
Film Comment. Vol. 21, No. 6; December 1985.
Film Fan Monthly.. No. 68, 79, 87, 89, 104, 130, 133 4, 145 6, 168; 1967 75 (gaps). Teaneck, NJ.
Film 1/24.(n.d.). Japan.
Film Library Quarterly. Vol. 10, No. 1/2, Vol. 11, No. 4; 1977-1978 (gaps).
Film Quarterly.. Vol. 31, No. 2; 1977 8.
Filmmakers Newsletter. Vol. 7, No. 3,6,8; Vol. 8, No. 3; 1974-1975 (gaps). New York, NY.
Funnyworld. No. 15, 17, 18, 20, 21, 23; 1973 83. Little Rock, AR.
Get Animated! No. 2,4; April 1985, September 1985.
Get Animated! Update. No. 2, 4; December 1986, February 1987. Burbank, CA.
Graffiti/In-between/The InBetweener (ASIFA). Sept. 1979-Feb. 1984 (gaps).
Heavy Metal. Vol. 5, No. 5.; August 1981.
Holland Animation Bulletin. Summer 1978, 1981. The Hague, Netherlands.
Hollywood Reporter.. Vol. 301, No. 15; February 25, 1988.
Horizon. Vol. 23, No. 3; March 1980.
How. Summer 1978, 1981. Vol. 1, No. 3, 4, 5; March/April - July/August 1986.
How. Vol. 2, No. 1, 5; November/December 1986, July/August 1987.
How. Vol. 2, No. 6, Vol. 3, No. 3, 5; September/October 1987, March/April 1988, July/August 1988.
The InBetweener. Vol. 2, No. 3; April 1984.
Japan Pictorial. Vol. 5, No. 2; 1982. Tokyo, Japan.
Kodak Professional Forum. Vol. 6, No. 1; 1983.
Kodak Professional Forum. Vol. 6, No. 1 (1983), Vol. 6, No. 1 (1984), Special Animation Issue, 1980 (mult. copies of each).
Mad. No. 8 (reprint); n.d.
Magical Moments and Memories. No. 12; Summer 1996.
Millimeter. Vol. 3, No. 1, 4, 7/8, 9, 10, 12; January - December 1975 (gaps).
Millimeter. Vol. 4, No. 2, 4, 6, 9, 10; February - October 1976 (gaps).
Millimeter. Vol. 5, No. 2, 5, 7, 9; February - October 1977 (gaps).
Millimeter/Funnyworld. Vol. 5, No. 2 (2 copies), No. 23; February 1997, Spring 1983.
Millimeter. Vol. 6, No. 2; Vol. 7, No. 2; Vol. 8, No. 2; Vol. 9, No. 2; February 1978 February 1981 (gaps)..
Mindrot. No. 3, 5, 6, 7 13; 1976 78 (gaps). Minneapolis, MN.
New York University Magazine. Vol. 4, No. 2; Fall 1989.
Newscaster. Vol. 24, No. 8; August 1984.
Newsreel. Vol. 27, No. 10,11,12; March 1998.
Pegboard. Vol. 27, No. 3,7; March 1998, July 1998. Los Angeles, CA.
Peg-Board.(Motion Picture Screen Cartoonists). Vol. 9, No. 2; 1978. Hollywood, CA.
Persistence of Vision. No. 8; 1996. Salt Lake City, UT.
Pop Art Times. March 1995.
Print. Vol. 32, No. 5, 6; September/October 1978, November/December 1978.
Print. Vol. 33, No. 2; Vol. 34, No. 6; Vol. 35, No. 5; March/April 1979, November/December 1980, September/October 1981.
Print. Vol. 36, No. 2; Vol. 37, No. 2; Vol. 38, No. 2; March/April 1982, March/April 1983, March/April 1984.
Print. Vol. 38, No. 5, Vol. 41, No. 3; September/October 1984, May/June 1987.
Print. Vol. 41, No. 5, 6; September/October 1987, November/December 1987.
Print. Vol. 42, No. 1, Vol. 44, No. 5; January/February 1988, September/October 1990.
Private Screenings. Vol. 1, No. 1; April/May 1975. Irvine, CA.
Relay. No. 2, Vol. 3, No. 2; October, 1982; May, 1984. Reseda, CA.
Sightlines.. Vol. 12, No. 2, 4; Vol. 18, No. 4/Vol. 19, No. 1; Vol. 19, No. 2, 3/4; 1978/9-1986 (gaps).
Sightlines.. Vol. 20, No. 2, 3, 4/Vol. 21, No. 1; Vol. 21, No. 2; 1986/7 1987/8 (gaps).
Sketches (Magazine of Walt Disney Collectors Society). Vol. 5, No.1; 1997.
Storyboard. Vol. 1, No. 1, 2, 4, 5; 1987 88 (gap). Anaheim Hills, CA.
Striprofiel. No. 5; Winter 1978/9. Amsterdam, Holland.
Take One. Vol. 7, No. 5; 1978..
Tomart's Disneyana Update. No. 7; 1995.
Twilight Bark (Walt Disney Feature Animation Department Newsletter). Vol. 9, No. 2,3; January, 1997.
White's Guide to Collecting Figures. Vol. 1, No. 11; November 1995.
Zoetrope. No. 3; March 1979. Chicago, IL.
Books
Adamson, Joe. The Walter Lantz Story. New York: Putnam's Sons, 1985.
American Film Institute Factfile #3: Film/Video Festivals and Awards. Los Angeles: AFI, 1983.
Animated Cartoons for the Beginner. Walter Foster Art Books, No. 25.
Annan, David. Movie Fantastic: Beyond the Dream Machine.[n.pl.]: Bounty Books, 1974.
Basic Titling and Animation for Motion Pictures. Eastman Kodak Company, 1972.
Beckerman, Howard. Animation the Whole Story. New York: Amereon House, 2001.
Benayoun, Robert. Le Dessin Anime Apres Walt Disney. Paris: Jean-Jacques Pauvert, 1961.
Blair, Preston. Animation. Walter Foster Art Books, No. 26.
Body, Veruschka. Clip, Klapp, Bum. Koln: DuMont, 1987.
Boxer, Sarah. In the Floyd Archives: a Psycho-Bestiary. New York: Pantheon Books, 2001.
Breslauer, Jan. The Making of the Rugrats Movie. Los Angeles: Klasky Csupo Publishing, 1998.
Canemaker, John. The Animated Raggedy Ann and Andy. New York, Bobbs-Merrill, 1977. [Signed copy]
Canemaker, John. Felix: The Twisted Tale of the World's Most Famous Cat. New York, Pantheon Books, 1991. [Signed copy]
Canemaker, John. Windsor McCay, His Life and Art. New York, Abbeville Press, 1987. [Signed copy]
Canemaker, John. Windsor McCay, His Life and Art (Revised and Expanded Edition). New York: Harry N. Abrams, 2005. [Signed copy]
Chevalier, Denys. J'aime le Dessin anime. Lausanne, Editions Recontre, 1962.
Cohen, Santiago. The Fifth Name. Washington: Fantagraphics Books, [n.d.]
Crowdus, Gary. Ed. The Political Companion to American Film. Chicago: Lakeview Press, 1994.
Daly, Kathleen N. Raggedy Ann and Andy. Indianapolis/New York: Bobbs-Merrill, 1977.
Diamant, Lincoln. Television's Classic Commercials. New York: Hastings House, 1971.
Dohler, Don. Stop Motion Animation. Baltimore: Cinema Enterprises, 1980.
Edera, Bruno. Full Length Animated Feature Films. New York: Hastings House, 1977.
Feild, Robert D. The Art of Walt Disney. New York: Macmillan, 1942.
Frames: A Selection of Drawings and Statements by Independent American Animators. George Griffin/Capitol Cities Press, 1978.
Grimault, Paul. L'Epouvantail Paris: Gallimard, 1946.
Halas, John. Art in Movement: New Directions in Animation. New York: Hastings House, 1970.
Halas, John. Film and TV Graphics. Zurich: Graphis Press, 1967.
Halas, John & Rider, David. The Great Movie Cartoon Parade. New York: Bounty Books, 1976.
Halas, John. Masters of Animation. Topsfield, MA: Salem House, 1987. [Annotated on notes]
Halas, John. The Technique of Film Animation New York: Hastings House, 1959.
Halas, John. Visual Scripting. New York: Hastings House, 1976.
Hall, Edward T. Hidden Differences: Studies in International Communications: Japan for Americans. New York: Hall Assoc., 1987.
Hall, Patricia. Johnny Gruelle, Creator of Raggedy Ann and Andy. Louisiana: Pelican Publishing Company, Inc., 1993.
Harryhausen, Ray. Film Fantasy Scrapbook. London: Barnes and Co., 1974.
Hayward, Stan. Scriptwriting for Animation. New York, Hastings House, 1977.
Herdeg, Walter. Film and TV Graphics 2. Zurich: Graphis Press, 1976.
Hogarth, Burne. Dynamic Figure Drawing. New York: Watson-Guptill, 1970.
Jacobs, Lewis. The Emergence of Film Art. New York: Hopkinson and Blake, 1969.
Jouvanceau, Pierre. Le Film de Silhouettes. / The Silhouette Film. Geneva: Le Mani, 2004.
Jungstedt, Torsten. Kapten Grogg och hans vanner. Stockholm: Svergiges Radios forlag, 1973. Includes separate english summary.
Kanfer, Stefan. Serious Business: The Art and Commerce of Animation in America from Betty Boop to Toy Story. New York: Scribner, 1997.
Karlsson, Ewert W. Great Figures of the World. Connecticut: Meckler Books, 1988.
Kelly, Walt. The Pogo Stepmother Goose. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1954.
Kukes, Roger. The Zoetrope Book. Portland, OR: Klassroom Kinetics, 1987.
Levitan, Eli. Animation Techniques and Commercial Film Production. New York: Reinhold, 1962.
McMahan, Harry Wayne. The Television Commercial: How to Create and Produce Effective TV Advertising. New York: Hastings House, 1954. Also 1957 edition.
Macek, Carl. The Art of Heavy Metal: The Movie. New York: Zoetrope, 1981.
Maltin, Leonard. The Disney Films. New York: Crown Publishers, 1973. [Presentation copy]
Manvell, Roger. Art & Animation: the Story of Halas & Batchelor Animation Studio 1940/1980. New York: Hastings House, 1980.
Martin the Cobbler. Minneapolis, MN: Winston Press, 1982.
Nilsen, Vladimir. The Cinema as a Graphic Art. New York: Hill and Wang, [n.d.]
O'Day, Tim. Disneyland--Celebrating 45 Years of Magic. New York: Roundtable Press, 2000.
Perisic, Zoran. The Animation Stand. New York: Focal Press, 1976.
Perisic, Zoran. The FocalGuide to Shooting Animation. London and New York: Focal Press, 1978.
Rubin, Susan. Animation: The Art and the Industry. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice-Hall, 1984.
Searle, Ronald. Dick Deadeye. New York and London: Harcourt Brace, 1975.
Solomon, Charles. The Complete Kodak Animation Book Rochester: Eastman Kodak, 1983.
Stockton, James. Designer's Guide to Color. San Francisco: Chronicle Books, 1984.
Toby. Silent Night with the Family Von Mouse. Hollywood, CA: Bluth Brothers/Pollinator, 1977.
Treasures of Disney Animation Art. Introduction by John Canemaker. New York: Abbeville Press, 1982. [Signed copy].
Trinchero, Sergio. I grandi eroi del cartone animato Americano. Roma: Ernesto Gremese, 1972.
Trudeau, Garry. A Doonesbury Special. Kansas City: Sheed Andrews and McMeel, 1977.
Walt Disney Presents The Jungle Book. New York: Golden Press, 1967.
Walt Disney's Bambi. Adapted by Melvin Shaw. New York: Golden Press, 1949.
Walt Disney's Fantasie da Fantasia. Milan: Arnoldo Mondadori Editore, 1989.
Walt Disney's Ferdinand the Bull. Racine, WI: Whitman Publishing, 1938.
Walt Disney's Mickey Mouse. Printed by Howard Bayliss, 1971.
Wentz, Budd. Paper Movie Machines. San Francisco: Troubador Press, 1975.
White, Tony. The Animator's Workbook. New York: Watson-Guptill, 1986.
Yoe, Craig & Morra-Yoe, Janet. The Art of Mickey Mouse. San Francisco: Chronicle Books, 1984.
Yoshitaka Amano & Hiroshi Unno Alice Erotica. Tokyo: 1999.
Alexeieff, Alexander; Baitt, Arthur; Children's television workshop.; Disney, Walt, 1901-1966; Fischinger, Elfriede; Fischinger, Oskar, 1900-1967; Lennon, John, 1940-1980; Marymount Manhattan College.; McCay, Winsor; Messmer, Otto, 1892-1983; Parker, Claire, 1906-1981; Tisch School of the Arts.; Walt Disney Productions. Treasures of Disney animation art; Williams, Richard, 1933-; Yale University.; Animated films |z United States.; Animation (Cinematography) |z United States |x History |y 20th century.; Animation (Cinematography) |z United States.; Animation.; Animators |z United States |v Interviews.; Animators |z United States.; Audiotapes.; Audiovisual materials.; Books.; Cartoonists |z United States |v Interviews.; Cartoonists |z United States |x Biography.; Drawings.; Fliers (printed matter); Flip books.; Galley proofs.; Monographs.; Motion pictures.; New York (N.Y.); Pamphlets.; Periodicals.; Posters.; Press releases.
- Series I:Documentary Material
  - Subseries A: Subjects
    - Advertising, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Animation Articles, undated (Box 34, Folder 61)
    - Art & Collecting, undated (Box 1, Folder 2-6)
    - Awards: American Film Institute, New York, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Awards: Annie Awards, Los Angeles, 1974 - 75, 1980 - 81, 1974-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bibliographies & Filmographies, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Conferences: ACM SIGGRAPH Conference, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 59)
    - Conferences: ACM SICGRAPH Conference, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 60)
    - Conferences: Walter Lantz Conf. on Animation, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Conferences: Walter Lantz Conf. on Animation, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 11-14)
    - Conferences: Midwest Film Conf.,Chicago, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Conferences: Teaching Animation, Italy, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Conferences: USC Annual AnimationFilm Conf., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Experimental Film, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Festivals & Screenings: Annecy (France), 1979-1985 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Festivals & Screenings: Atlanta, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Festivals & Screenings: Bristol (UK), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Festivals & Screenings: Cambridge, MA, 1977, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Festivals & Screenings: Cambridge (UK), 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Festivals & Screenings: Cardiff, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Festivals & Screenings: Trickfilm, Chicago, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Festivals & Screenings: USA Film Fest.,Dallas, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Festivals & Screenings: Cinanima,Espinho (Portugal), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Festivals & Screenings:Hiroshima, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Festivals & Screenings: La Jolla, CA, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Festivals & Screenings: AnimationCelebration, Los Angeles, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Festivals &Screenings: FILMEX, Los Angeles, 1978, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Festivals & Screenings: Lucca (Italy), 1986 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Festivals &Screenings: Montreal (Canada), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Festivals &Screenings: American Film & Video Fest., New York, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Festivals & Screenings: ASIFA - EAST Program, New York, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Festivals & Screenings: Film Forum, New York, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Festivals & Screenings: InternationalTournee of Animation, New York, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Festivals &Screenings: Lincoln Center Walt Disney 50th Anniversary Film Retrospective, New York, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Festivals & Screenings: New Animation,New York, 1976, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Festivals & Screenings:New York Cultural Center, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Festivals &Screenings: Superfilmshow, New York, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Festivals &Screenings: Thalia Cartoonal Knowledge, New York, n.d., undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Festivals & Screenings: Ottawa (Canada), 1976 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Festivals & Screenings: Ottawa (Canada), 1978 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Festivals & Screenings: United States Film Fest., Park City, Utah, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Festivals & Screenings: Santa Fe, NM, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Festivals & Screenings: Zagreb(Yugoslavia), 1982 (Box 4, Folder 45-46)
    - International: Canada, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - International: China, undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - International: France, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - International: Hungary, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - International: Japan, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - International: United Kingdom, undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - International: USSR, undated (Box 34, Folder 63)
    - LaborRelations, undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Television, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Theory & Technique, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Miscellaneous Subjects, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Minor Festivals and Shows, 1970-1981 (Box 34, Folder 62)
  - Subseries B: People
    Scope and Contents note
    - Aaron, Jane, undated (Box 40, Folder 352)
    - Alexeieff, Alexander & Parker, Claire, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Avery, Tex, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Babbitt, Art, undated (Box 5, Folder 3-7)
    - Babbitt, Art, undated (Box 32, Folder 289)
    - Baer, Dale, undated (Box 16, Folder 171)
    - Bakshi, Ralph, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Bakshi, Ralph, undated (Box 40, Folder 346)
    - Banyi, Istvan, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Barre, Raoul, undated (Box 27, Folder 345)
    - Bass,Jules ***see*** Rankin, Arthur, undated (Box 5)
    - Batchelor, Joy***see*** Halas, John, undated (Box 5)
    - Bell, Carl, undated (Box 5, Folder 10.1)
    - Belson, Jordan, undated (Box 5, Folder 10.2)
    - Blair, Mary ("Lee"), undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Blair, Mary, undated (Box 36, Folder 317)
    - Blair, Mary, undated (Box 37, Folder 318-321)
    - Blair, Mary, undated (Box 27, Folder 322)
    - Blanc, Mel, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Bluth, Don, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Budrero, James, undated (Box 30, Folder 275)
    - Bowers, Charles, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Bozetto, Bruno, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Bray, John R, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Bray, John R, undated (Box 40, Folder 348)
    - Bunin, Lou, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Bute, Mary Ellen, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Canemaker, John: General, undated (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
    - Canemaker, John: Articles by Canemaker, undated (Box 39, Folder 339)
    - Canemaker, John: Action Analysis, undated (Box 32, Folder 293-295)
    - Canemaker, John: Books: The Animated Raggedy Ann..., undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Canemaker, John: Books: Winsor McCay, undated (Box 17, Folder 180-196)
    - Canemaker, John: Books: Winsor McCay, undated (Box 36, Folder 312-317)
    - Canemaker, John: Books: Winsor McCay, undated (Box 42, Folder 373-377)
    - Canemaker, John: Books: Felix: the Twisted Tale..., undated (Box 18, Folder 200-213)
    - Canemaker, John: Books: Felix: the Twisted Tale..., undated (Box 26, Folder 248)
    - Canemaker, John: Books: Felix: the Twisted Tale..., undated (Box 41, Folder 367-372)
    - Canemaker, John: Books: Before the Animation Begins, undated (Box 35, Folder 308-311)
    - Canemaker, John: Books: Tex Avery, undated (Box 42, Folder 379-380)
    - Canemaker, John: Books: Tex Avery, undated (Box 43, Folder 381-383)
    - Canemaker, John: Clippings, undated (Box 42, Folder 378)
    - Canemaker, John: Research Paper: Golden Age of Disney, undated (Box 39, Folder 333-337)
    - Canemaker, John: Films: ANIMATIONAROUND THE WORLD, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Canemaker, John:Films: BOTTOM'S DREAM, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Canemaker, John:Films: BREAKING THE SILENCE, undated (Box 21, Folder 225-226)
    - Canemaker, John:Films: CHILDREN'S TELEVISION WORKSHOP: DNA CONCERTO, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Canemaker, John: Films: CHILDREN'S TELEVISION WORKSHOP:80 MILLION YEARS AGO, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Canemaker, John:Films: CHILDREN'S TELEVISION WORKSHOP: SHAPE OF MATH, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Canemaker, John: CONFESSIONS OF A STARDREAMER, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Canemaker, John: COUNT ON KOTEXcommercial, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Canemaker, John: THE40'S, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Canemaker, John: GREED, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Canemaker, John: THE HOUSE ON 88TH STREET, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Canemaker, John: THE HUNGERPROJECT, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Canemaker, John: JOHNLENNON SKETCHBOOK, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Canemaker, John: LATE FOR DINNER, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Canemaker, John: LAUGHTER IS GOOD MEDICINE, undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Canemaker,John: LUST, undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Canemaker, John: MUSIC,MUSIC, MUSIC, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Canemaker, John: NEMO***see*** Thomas, Frank & Johnston, Ollie, undated (Box 7)
    - Canemaker, John: OTTO MESSMER & FELIX THE CAT, undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Canemaker, John: REMEMBERING WINSOR MCCAY, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Canemaker, John: RISING STAR VIDEO logo, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)